propertyfinder.com 2016-12-29

# Zoopla Privacy policy - Zoopla

Zoopla Property Group Plc (" **Zoopla** ", **we** or **us** ) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. 

This policy (together with our terms of use and any other documents referred to in it) sets out the basis on which any personal information we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal information and how we will treat it. By visiting this website you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy. 

We may amend this privacy policy at any time. Any changes we may make will be posted on this page, so please check back frequently. Your continued use of our website(s) will constitute your acceptance of, and agreement to, any changes to the privacy policy. 

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act), the data controller is Zoopla Property Group Plc of The Cooperage, 5 Copper Row, London. SE1 2LH. Zoopla Property Group Plc and the subsidiaries it controls are referred to in this privacy policy, collectively, as the Zoopla Group of Companies and, individually, as a Zoopla Group Company. 

## Information we may collect from you

We may collect and process the following information about you: 

  * **Information you provide to us**. You may provide us with information by filling in forms on our website(s) or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you register for an account or subscribe, contact estate agents via forms or phone numbers made available on our website, enter a competition, promotion or survey, provide feedback and/or when you report a problem with our website. The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number. 
  * **Information we collect about you**. When you visit our website(s) we may automatically collect information about your computer, including your IP address, information about your visit, your browsing history, and how you use our website(s). This information may be combined with other information you provide to us, as described above. 
  * **Information we receive from other sources**. We may receive information about you if you use any of the other websites we, or Zoopla Group Companies, operate or the other services we provide. We are also working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, service providers, advertising networks, analytics providers, and search information providers) and may receive information about you from them. This information may be combined with other information you provide to us, as described above. 

## How we use your personal information

We use personal information about you in connection with the following purposes: 

  * Fulfilling your requests: 
    * to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us or another Zoopla Group Company; 
    * to administer any promotion or competition that you enter via our website(s); and 
    * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so. 
  * Marketing: 
    * to provide you, or permit other Zoopla Group Companies, or selected third parties to provide you, with information about goods or services that may interest you; 
    * to customise or enhance your experience on our website(s) and services, including via the display of adverts and direct communications you receive from us which may be based on your activity on our website(s) or the website of another Zoopla Group Company; 
    * to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you, which may be based on your activity on our website(s) or the website of another Zoopla Group Company; and 
    * to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our website about goods or services that may interest you or them, which may be based on your activity on our website(s) or the website of another Zoopla Group Company. 
  * Service improvements and account management: 
    * to notify you about changes to our service and to send you service emails relating to your account; 
    * to administer our website(s) and for internal business administration and operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes; 
    * to provide information and services to estate agents that allow them to monitor and benchmark their own performance; and 
    * as part of our efforts to keep our website(s) safe and secure. 

## Sharing your personal information

We may share your personal information in connection with the purposes above with any other Zoopla Group Company. 

We may also share your personal information with third parties in the following circumstances: 

  * Selected estate agents or other service providers, when you have asked us to do so. For example, when you enquire about a property of interest to you, we will pass your personal information to the estate agents handling that property sale or rental. Upon receipt of your personal information, the relevant third party is the data controller and their use of your information will be governed by their own terms of use and privacy policy. 
  * Business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you. 
  * Advertisers and advertising networks and other third parties that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others. 
  * Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our website(s). Your personal information is generally shared in a form that does not directly identify you. 

We may also share your personal information with third parties: 

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal information to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets, along with its professional advisers. If Zoopla or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, personal information held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets. 
  * If required in order to obtain professional advice. 
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal information in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Zoopla, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection. 

## Where we store your personal information

The information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored, in a country outside the European Economic Area (EEA). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. The laws in some countries may not provide as much legal protection for your information as in the EEA. By submitting your information, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. 

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone. 

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your information transmitted to our website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. 

## Cookies

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our website and to provide interest-based advertising. You may adjust the settings on your browser to refuse cookies but some of the services on our website(s) may not work if you do so. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them see our Cookie Policy. 

## Opting Out of Collection of Information by Third Parties

Zoopla Property Group Plc’s third-party ad servers, ad network providers, and third-party advertisers (the **_ZPG Group Ad Providers_** ) may provide you with advertisements that you may see on our website(s) or on other affiliated websites. To improve the relevancy and help measure the effectiveness of such advertisements, the ZPG Group Ad Providers may use cookies, web beacons, clear .gifs or similar technologies. These are used to record users’ activity, such as the pages visited, and to learn what types of information are of most interest to the users. Use of these technologies by ZPG Group Ad Providers is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by our privacy policy. For more information regarding the choices you have about these technologies (such as opting-out), [click here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). 

## Your rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal information for marketing purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking or unchecking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data, unsubscribing via any marketing emails we send or amending your details in  MyZoopla . 

Our website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers, affiliates or other third parties. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal information to these websites. 

## Access to information

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. 

Updated: September 2016
